Contact

PO BOX 216 Rio Frio, TX 78879 jillcaten@live.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jill-caten-052640a2 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Labor & Delivery Nursing Newborn Nursery Care Postpartum Nursing Care

Certifications
BLS
NRP
S.T.A.B.L.E.
ACLS

Jill Caten

Travel RN at Women's Hospital of Texas at Conroe Regional Medical Center

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

I have more than twenty years of experience in the field of nursing, in various capacities. Five years ago, I decided to switch gears and pursue training in maternal and fetal health. For the past two years, I have been a travel nurse, working as a contractor in hospitals all over the United States. Many of these hospitals have been teaching institutions, and I have discovered an interest in teaching, often being complimented for my ability to teach and my patience in teaching. I have also developed skill in coming into any situation, and adapting to their systems and culture quickly. I am energetic and outgoing, and I love the adventure of traveling, meeting new people, and seeing new things.

Even further back in my career, at M. D. Anderson Cancer Center, I found that I enjoyed teaching, working with colleagues, patients, and fellows, training them to use the newest technologies in pain management. I gained experience in public speaking and presenting, as well as more informal training in a clinical setting. I have a strong commitment to personal and professional excellence, with excellent written and oral communication skills. I am known as a passionate and empathetic nurse, and a strong advocate for my patients.

Experience

The Women's Hospital of Texas at Conroe Regional Medical Center Travel RN, Labor & Delivery November 2014 - June 2015 (8 months)

Conroe, Texas

Provide nursing care to the perinatal patient, working in Labor & Delivery, Newborn Nursery, and Postpartum units. This hospital delivers approximately 200 infants per year, experiencing more than double their growth in the past year. Provide normal and high-risk care in a teaching hospital. Utilize Meditech and Centricity/QS computer systems.

University Health System Travel RN, Labor & Delivery July 2014 - October 2014 (4 months)

San Antonio, Texas Area

This was a 13-week travel contract at this county teaching hospital. This is a very busy, fast-paced unit that serves as a high-risk services provider for many surrounding counties. There is a very high ratio of complicated patients, and they deliver 250-300 infants per month, using the Sunrise computer system. Includes acute antepartum care and circulating and recovering c-sections.

Jackson North Medical Center Travel RN, Labor & Delivery April 2014 - July 2014 (4 months) North Miami, Florida

This was a 9-week contract to assist with an EMR conversion as a staff nurse at this county hospital in Miami-Dade County, FL. This is a very busy unit, delivering approximately 2,000 infants per year at a teaching hospital. Position included high-risk care, as well as circulating and recovering c-sections. This hospital utilizes a combination of Cerner and Centricity computer systems.

St. David's HealthCare
Travel RN, Labor & Delivery
September 2013 - April 2014 (8 months)

I returned to do a second 25-week contract as a staff nurse at this very busy Women's Center that delivers approximately 8,000 infants per year. I provided normal and high-risk care, and circulated and recovered c-sections. I was frequently called upon to precept nursing students, doing clinical studies at this hospital. This hospital utilizes Meditech and Centricity computer systems.

University of Minnesota Medical Center, Fairview Travel RN, Labor & Delivery July 2013 - September 2013 (3 months)

Travel Nurse, Birthplace. I worked as a staff nurse at this large, busy tertiary care center and teaching hospital. This included an increased ratio of highrisk patients in Labor and Delivery, Antepartum, and Postpartum units. Approximately 250 births per month. This was a 13-week travel contract. This hospital used EPIC computer system, and Centricity for surveillance.

West Kauai Medical Center Travel RN, Labor & Delivery/Level I Nursery

April 2013 - July 2013 (4 months)

Waimea, Kauai, Hawaii

I worked as a staff nurse at this small community, critical access hospital that delivers 350 infants per year, providing L&D, postpartum, and nursery care, including circulating and recovering c-sections. High risk cases were stabilized and transferred out. This was a 13-week travel contract. This hospital utilized paper charting.

St. David's HealthCare

Travel RN, Labor & Delivery December 2012 - April 2013 (5 months)

I worked as a staff nurse at this very busy Women's Center that delivers approximately 8,000 infants per year. Provided normal and high-risk care, circulated and recovered c-sections. This was a 16-week travel contract. Utilized Meditech and Centricity computer systems.

Los Alamos Medical Center

Travel RN, Labor & Delivery

September 2012 - November 2012 (3 months)

Los Alamos, New Mexico

I worked as a staff nurse at this community hospital that delivers approximately 200 infants per year. Provided L&D, Postpartum and Nursery care. This was a Level II Nursery. This was a 10-week travel contract.

Women and Infants Hospital

Travel RN, Mother/Baby Care

June 2012 - September 2012 (4 months)

Travel contract position for 13 weeks. I worked as a staff nurse, providing couplet care, at this very busy hospital that delivers approximately 8,500 infants per year. Utilized Cerner computer system.

Scott & White Healthcare

Staff Nurse II, Labor & Delivery, Postpartum, Antepartum, and Newborn Nursery

April 2009 - May 2012 (3 years 2 months)

Brenham, Texas

I worked as a staff nurse at this rural hospital, developing skills in all areas

L. Being a rural hospital that delivers approximately 35 newborns per month, strong skills in all areas of maternal/newborn care, as well as sharp critical thinking skills were essential. Participated on performance improvement

teams and Service Excellence team. Utilized Centricity and Meditech computer systems.

Mainland Pain Consultants
Clinical Nurse Manager
March 2008 - January 2009 (11 months)
Dickinson, Texas

I worked as a clinical nurse manager for this very busy private pain practice. The scope of the practice included interventional pain management, such as blocks, intrathecal pumps, and spinal cord stimulation, as well as medical management of pain. Responsibilities included supervision of clinical staff and operations, management of patients with intrathecal pumps, refilling and programming the pumps, patient assessment and teaching, telephone triage, and pre-op and recovery of patients who had undergone conscious sedation for procedures.

Center for the Relief of Pain Clinical Outpatient Nurse January 2006 - March 2008 (2 years 3 months) Webster, Texas

I worked as a clinic nurse for this private pain practice. Responsibilities included administering and monitoring conscious sedation and assisting the physician with interventional pain management procedures. I also managed and programmed intrathecal pumps for patients with these implanted pumps. This position required strong patient assessment skills, telephone triage, patient teaching, ordering and stocking supplies, strong customer service skills, and all other back-office duties.

MD Anderson Cancer Center

Clinical Nurse, Outpatient, Pain Management and Palliative Care June 2000 - January 2006 (5 years 8 months)

. I participated on a multidisciplinary team that provided multi-symptom management of patients with chronic pain, cancer, and terminal illness. I joined the Pain Management Center as the primary clinic nurse to the Section Chief of Pain Management. Responsibilities in this fast-paced clinic included all aspects of management of patients in an outpatient clinic setting, including interventional pain management, medical management, and management of patients with implanted devices, such as spinal cord stimulators and intrathecal pumps, as well as telephone triage, patient teaching, and coordination of care within a multidisciplinary team. I was a trusted resource for colleagues,

students, and patients and I shared my knowledge by presenting information on pain management, including management of pain with implanted devices, both in informal, one-on-one settings and as a keynote speaker for more formal presentations.

Hospice of Integrated Health Services RN Case Manager, promoted to Director of Clinical Services May 1998 - May 2000 (2 years 1 month)

Responsibilities included RN case management for patients diagnosed with a terminal illness. I provided nursing care to the dying in their homes, assisting them to have quality of life and a peaceful death with dignity. Was promoted to Director of Clinical Services, which included supervision of all clinical staff and clinical operations.

Hospice Preferred Choice RN Case Manager August 1997 - April 1998 (9 months) Houston, Texas Area

Provided nursing care and case management to patients diagnosed with a terminal illness. Worked in home, nursing home, and inpatient hospital settings. Worked with an interdisciplinary team, assisting patients to have quality of life and a dignified death.

Memorial Hermann Health System
Pre-Admission Nurse, Staff Nurse
June 1994 - August 1997 (3 years 3 months)

Responsibilities as a Pre-Admission Nurse included screening and education of patients prior to admission for elective surgeries and non-emergency medical admissions. Required extensive relations with physicians and their office staff. Prior to working as Pre-Admission Nurse, I started my nursing career with Memorial Hermann as a staff nurse in Med-Surg and Pediatrics, PCU, and SNF Units.

Exxon Company, USA Staff Administrative Secretary October 1988 - June 1992 (3 years 9 months)

Worked as a secretary to six landmen in the Land Management Department. Responsibilities included preparing inspection reports, budgets, and correspondence, as well as making travel arrangements, maintaining calendars, and all other general office duties. Excelled as a leader in learning and teaching new technologies, as the computer revolution came about.

Decision Data Service
Dispatcher/Secretary
March 1986 - June 1988 (2 years 4 months)

Responsibilities included intake of service calls for this computer repair company, then dispatching these calls to service technicians in the field.

Required use of key maps for South Texas area, strong organizational skills and customer service skills. Also performed secretarial duties, such as organizing meetings, preparing correspondence, filing and receptionist duties.

Hoyt & Kahn, Attorneys at Law Legal Secretary June 1984 - October 1986 (2 years 5 months) Humble, Texas

Worked as a legal secretary to two attorneys specializing in civil, family, probate, and real estate law. Responsibilities included preparing legal documents for filing, preparing correspondence, maintaining calendars and files, and all other general office duties.

Education

Alvin Community College

Associate of Applied Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (1992 - 1994)

North Harris Montgomery County College System No degree earned, General Studies · (1990 - 1991)

Humble High School
Diploma, General Studies · (1981 - 1985)